As an example for a classification problem,
作为分类问题的一个例子
we will predict a tag for the questions.
我们要预测问题的标签是什么
For this task, we will use the one tag field,
对于这个任务 我们会使用 onetag 字段
I already talked a bit about in the previous video.
我在之前的视频中已经介绍过了
So, one tag is just the most common tag a question has.
Onetag 是问题中最常见的标签
So, we can simplify this multi-target problem into a single target one.
这样我们就可以把多目标问题简化为单个目标问题
As our feature, let's just use the TF-IDF we computed in one of the earlier videos,
我们会使用之前视频中计算出的 TF-IDF 作为特征
and train a basic logistic regression model.
然后训练一个基本的逻辑回归模型
If you recall, we created label from the one.com earlier.
如果你还记得 我们之前从 onetag 列创建了标签列
So, label has a numeric value as well as TF-IDF already is sparse vector,
Label列有数值 TF-IDF已经是稀疏向量
so this will work for our model just like this.
这直接可以当作模型的输入了
The dataset has 301 different tags.
数据集有 301 个不同的标签
So, our model missus side which one of
所以 我们的模型要判断哪个标签是
these is the most likely for a particular question.
特定问题最可能的标签
All right? Our model has been trained.
好的我们的模型已经训练好了
So now, we can check its parameters.
现在 我们来看看它的参数
Since we are dealing with a multi-class classification problem,
因为我们在处理多类分类问题
we will have a coefficient matrix rather than just a vector of coefficients,
我们将有一个系数矩阵 而不仅仅是一个系数向量
and then intercept vector instead of just a single value on intercept.
单个截距值也会变成截距向量
So, we have a matrix here with 301 rows,
我们有一个 301 行 1000列的矩阵
and it has some columns as well as the intercept vector.
以及截距向量
Let's show the accuracy of our model.
接下来我们看看模型的准确率
All right, so with using
好吧 我们只用了
only the TF-IDF of the most common thousand words in the questions,
TF-IDF处理最常见的 1000 个单词
but we get an accuracy of around 36 percent.
但我们的准确率约为 36％
So, how good is this result?
那么这个结果怎么样 ？
We have about a 100,000 rows in our dataset,
我们的数据集中有大约 100,000 行
and 301 different tags.
和 301 个不同的标签
So, if the tags were uniformly distributed in our dataset,
如果标签在我们的数据集中均匀分布
the random chance of getting the deck right would be one over 301,
随机猜中右侧标签的概率是1/301
that's a bigger number around three percent,
也就是大约3％的猜中概率
but there are certainly tags that are more common than other ones.
但数据集里有些标签肯定比其他标签更常见
The most common tag is assigned to about five percent of the records.
最常见的标签大约占了记录的5％
So, still 36 percent isn't too bad.
所以 36％ 准确率还是不错的
We could of course, explore how including more features,
我们还可以把更多的特征加进来
different model parameters might improve this result,
不同的模型参数可能会对结果有所改善
but we will leave this for another time.
但是这块内容我们下次再讲吧
I would also like to mention that we computed this accuracy on the dataset,
我还想再提一下 我们是用的
we trained the model.
训练集做的预测 这个操作是不对的
So, of course this is probably a bit too optimistic.
这个结果可能有点过于乐观了
We will see how to do this more properly in a later video
后面的视频里我们会演示正确的操作